How much food do you buy each week?
你每周买多少食物呢？
Are you someone who stuffs your fridge and cupboards full of edible treats so that you‘ll always have something to munch on and so that you’ll never go hungry?
你是不是那种把冰箱和橱柜都塞满可食用的美味食品的人，这样你就总是有东西可以咀嚼，而且永远不会挨饿呢？
Or maybe, like me, you‘re more efficient with your shopping, only buying what you need and using up your leftovers so that you keep food waste to a minimum.
或者，也许像我一样，你在购物方面更有效率，只买你需要的东西，把剩菜剩饭都吃光，以便将食物浪费降到最低限度。
Throwing away unwanted food has become a big issue in the developed world.
在发达国家，扔掉不需要的食物已经成为一个大问题。
While some of us chuck away unwanted items, people in other parts of world face food shortages and are starving.
当我们中的一些人扔掉不需要的东西时，世界其他地区的人们却面临着食物短缺，正在挨饿。
It’s a shocking fact that a third of the world‘s food is wasted each year.
一个令人震惊的事实是，世界上每年有三分之一的食物被浪费掉。
The actual figure is 1.3 billion tons of food, which is enough to feed a billion hungry people.
实际数字是13亿吨食物，这足以养活10亿饥饿的人。
You might think supermarkets are the main contributors to this mountain of waste.
你可能会认为超市是造成这堆积如山的食物浪费的主要促成因素。
After all, they do discard stuff that has passed its sell-by-date, and they often refuse to sell vegetables or fruit that are oddly shaped or look damaged.
毕竟，他们确实会丢弃那些过了保质期的东西，而且他们经常拒绝出售形状不好或看起来有损坏的蔬菜或水果。
They’ve also been criticised for encouraging customers to buy more than they need through promotions such as ‘buy one get one free‘.
他们还因为通过“买一送一”等促销活动鼓励顾客购买超过他们需要的东西而受到批评。
But the biggest culprit for creating food waste is us.
但造成食物浪费的最大罪魁祸首是我们自己。
In Europe an incredible 53% of food waste comes from households, which results in 88 million tonnes of food waste a year.
在欧洲，令人难以置信的是，53%的食物浪费来自家庭，这导致每年产生8800万吨的食物浪费。
So instead of filling our bellies, our food is filling up landfill sites — it’s buried and left to rot.
所以，我们的食物不是填饱我们的肚子，而是填满了垃圾填埋场——它们被掩埋起来任其腐烂。
Unfortunately this causes greenhouse gases which eventually leads to global warming and climate change.
不幸的是，这会产生温室气体，最终导致全球变暖和气候变化。
In Denmark, a woman called Selina Juul has been working hard to tackle this problem.
在丹麦，一位名叫塞琳娜·尤尔的女士一直在努力解决这个问题。
She moved from Russia many years ago and was amazed to see the abundance of food available in the supermarkets.
她多年前从俄罗斯搬到这里，惊讶于超市里食物的丰富多样。
But despite so much availability, she found that people were buying more than they needed and throwing too much away.
但是，尽管有这么多的食物，她发现人们购买远超他们所需要的食物，而且也扔掉了太多的食物。
She convinced some supermarkets to stop selling their items in bulk so that people bought only what they needed.
她说服了一些超市停止批量地销售商品，这样人们就只购买他们需要的东西。
She produced a leftovers cookbook and she‘s now set up an education programme in schools.
她制作了一本剩菜食谱，现在她还在学校设立了一个教育项目。
This has helped create a significant 25% reduction in food waste, which shows that something can be done.
这使得食物浪费显著减少了25%，这表明我们是可以有所作为的。
Clearly, we need to think twice when we put something in our shopping trolley, and when we’re at home we should make the most of the food we have - using recipes that use up our leftovers or even sharing our excess food with our friends and neighbours.
显然，当我们把东西放进购物车的时候，我们需要三思而后行，而当我们在家的时候，我们应该充分利用我们所拥有的食物——使用可以把剩菜用光的食谱，甚至可以和我们的朋友和邻居分享我们多余的食物。